<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Melissa Jay Smith</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Melissa Jay Smith</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Melissa Jay Smith</title>
      <link>/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/</guid>
      <description>img {border-radius: 50%;}Thanks for visiting my website! My name is Melissa Smith, and I am an Assistant Professor in the Department of Biostatistics at the University of Alabama at Birmingham. My statistical research interests are in the areas of Bayesian statistics, disease mapping, spatial statistics, and mediation analysis. I also enjoy collaborating with researchers across disciplines on studies in public health and medicine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>Published:Jay M, Oleson J, Charlton M, Arab A. A Bayesian approach for estimating age-adjusted rates for low-prevalence diseases over space and time. Statistics in Medicine. 2021;40(12):2922-2938.
Sewell DK, Penney J, Jay M, Zhang Y, Paulsen JS. Predicting an optimal composite outcome variable for Huntington&#39;s disease clinical trials. Journal of Applied Statistics. 2021;48(7):1339-1348. 
Jay M, Betensky RA. Displaying survival of patient groups defined by covariate paths: Extensions of the Kaplan-Meier estimator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selected Presentations</title>
      <link>/presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/presentations/</guid>
      <description>Modeling age-adjusted rates from spatio-temporal data sets with excess zero counts. Conference on Statistical Practice. Virtual presentation. 2021. 
Understanding &#34;how&#34; in a study of cause and effect: An introduction to mediation analysis in epidemiology. University of Iowa INFORMS Student Chapter Knowledge Cafe. Virtual presentation. 2020. 
Displaying survival of patient groups defined by covariate paths: Extensions of the Kaplan-Meier estimator. Eastern North American Region International Biometric Society Spring Meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
