<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Melissa Jay Smith</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Melissa Jay Smith</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Media</title>
      <link>/media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/media/</guid>
      <description>p {text-align: center;}Goldwater Scholar Community NSF GRFP Webinar
  Goldwater Scholar Community Graduate School Webinar
  Resources for Undergraduates (my tweets from the @WomenInStat account)Where can you find undergraduate summer opportunities in statistics, biostatistics, and data science in the US? A thread. 1/
&amp;mdash; Women in Statistics and Data Science (@WomenInStat) August 24, 2021  Since the graduate program application season is approaching, I thought I’d share some questions that might be helpful to ask when choosing a biostatistics/ statistics graduate program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melissa Jay Smith</title>
      <link>/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/</guid>
      <description>img {border-radius: 50%;}Thanks for visiting my website! My name is Melissa Smith, and I am an Assistant Professor in the Department of Biostatistics at the University of Alabama at Birmingham. My statistical research interests are in the areas of Bayesian statistics, disease mapping, spatial statistics, and mediation analysis. I also enjoy collaborating with researchers across disciplines on studies in public health and medicine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>Published:Jay M, Oleson J, Charlton M, Arab A. A Bayesian approach for estimating age-adjusted rates for low-prevalence diseases over space and time. Statistics in Medicine. 2021;40(12):2922-2938.
Sewell DK, Penney J, Jay M, Zhang Y, Paulsen JS. Predicting an optimal composite outcome variable for Huntington&#39;s disease clinical trials. Journal of Applied Statistics. 2021;48(7):1339-1348. 
Jay M, Betensky RA. Displaying survival of patient groups defined by covariate paths: Extensions of the Kaplan-Meier estimator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources for students</title>
      <link>/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/</guid>
      <description>Mentorship programs (undergraduate, pre-graduate, and/or pre-PhD)
Project SHORT: “Comprised of volunteer professional health and graduate students, residents, faculty, and post-docs, Project SHORT (Students for Higher-Ed Opportunities and Representation in Training) is the first organization to offer pro bono mentoring for both professional health and graduate school admissions.” (Project SHORT website)Project SHORT has both a mentorship program and many resources on the graduate school application process, interview process, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selected Presentations</title>
      <link>/presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/presentations/</guid>
      <description>Modeling age-adjusted rates from spatio-temporal data sets with excess zero counts. Conference on Statistical Practice. Virtual presentation. 2021. 
Understanding &#34;how&#34; in a study of cause and effect: An introduction to mediation analysis in epidemiology. University of Iowa INFORMS Student Chapter Knowledge Cafe. Virtual presentation. 2020. 
Displaying survival of patient groups defined by covariate paths: Extensions of the Kaplan-Meier estimator. Eastern North American Region International Biometric Society Spring Meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service</title>
      <link>/service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/service/</guid>
      <description>Leadership
President, Biostatistics Student Organization (BSO), University of Iowa (2020 - 2021)
President &amp;amp; Student Founder, Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics Student Chapter, Colorado College (2013 - 2015)
Received the Leon F. Burmeister Graduate Student Service Award (2021) and the SIAM Student Chapter Certificate of Recognition (2015) for my exemplary leadership in these roles
Mentorship
Pre-Grad Mentor, Project SHORT (2021)
Project Mentor, Iowa Summer Institute in Biostatistics (2021)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Iowa Summer Institute in Biostatistics
The Iowa Summer Institute in Biostatistics (ISIB) is an NIH-funded summer institute focused on introducing undergraduates to the field of biostatistics. While at Iowa, I have had the opportunity to serve as both a Lab Instructor and Project Mentor for the ISIB program.
Lab Instructor for BIOS:4110 General Biostatistics (Summer 2019, Summer 2021)
Project Mentor (Summer 2021)
University of Iowa</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
